jason johnson

Novato, California, United States



blaholdings@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/jason-johnson-006424

Summary

Software Product, Project and Program Management veteran with nearly 15 years experience leading teams in successfully defining and delivering highly available, highly scalable online technologies across multiple industries and business environments.

Product Management Project Management Program Management Market and Customer Analysis Partner & Dependency Management Scenarios / Use Cases / User Stories Product Design and Planning Issue / Risk Mitigation **Budgeting and Scheduling** Development, Delivery & Support **Technical Architecture**

I'm always interested in hearing about new opportunities to take my career to the next level. Don't hesitate to reach out!

Experience



Sr. Technical Product Manager

Twitch

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Doing stuff with APIs and Analytics for AWS IVS (https://aws.amazon.com/ivs/). Stay tuned!

⋜ Sr. Technical Product Manager, Head of Product

2K

Aug 2015 - Jun 2022 (6 years 11 months)

Head of product for a 50+ person engineering team delivering and operating a suite of online service verticals supporting 2K and its game studios. These verticals included identity and single sign-on, telemetry, commerce, advertising, multiplayer, and an extensible cloud engineering framework.

- Balanced explicit business asks, competitive analysis and intuition to prioritize and develop product requirements in the form of diagrams, user stories, UX mocks and other documentation
- Drove adoption and investment by evangelizing current and future product capabilities through documentation, roadmaps, presentations and recorded demos
- Mentored direct reports and other engineering discipline leaders in product and program management principals as well as technical product excellence

- Partnered with engineering leadership to develop platform architecture and review interface and object model designs in order to ensure alignment with business requirements and platform scalability
- Over three years, grew the team from only 6 engineers supporting around 80 APIs to a 50+ person organization delivering nearly 400 APIs across 6 service verticals and counting
- Partnered with executive leadership to transform product platform from a prototype supporting a small subset of titles to the de-facto service provider for all current and future titles

Sr. Program Manager - Bing Developer Experiences

Microsoft

2012 - 2014 (2 years)

Promoted to help lead development of multiple initiatives related to a new Bing Developer Experiences strategy and later drive efforts related to Microsoft's partnership in the Schema.org standards initiative.

- Partnered with principal leadership to establish the new Bing Data Publishing and Developer Experiences organization. Led team of 10 engineers in design, development, and delivery of a data management web portal platform.
- Successfully partnered cross-org to deliver data management web portal for Xbox Live which eliminated over \$1 million in vendor costs and reduced time-to-market from months to days
- Tapped to lead Microsoft's investments in Schema.org acting as chief technical evangelist and tripling the number of Microsoft teams adopting the standard while also doubled internal engagement in less than a year

Program Manager - Bing Mobile / Local

Microsoft

2010 - 2012 (2 years)

Served as a program manager in the Bing Mobile and Bing Local organizations working on multiple initiatives exploring new ways to leverage Bing search technology to power innovative applications.

- Recruited to help define, design, and deliver a prototype mobile app that explored application of new technologies and concepts in the area of local business search.
- Led multiple teams in delivering a pair of prototype search technologies from initial concept through development and delivery. Both technologies laid the foundation for multiple long-term initiatives.

Program Manager [Contract] - Microsoft UPG

Microsoft

2009 - 2010 (1 year)

Owned delivery of the messaging and notification features for a virtual java platform targeted at mobile phones in developing countries. Led a small team of engineers, serving as product owner and SCRUM master in agile development model. Excellence in project management over the course of the contract led to a full-time position at Microsoft.

motricity Product Manager

Motricity

2006 - 2008 (2 years)

Responsible for various projects involving solution definition, project management, sales engineering and account management

- Successfully led a team of engineers in launching 13 major mobile search feature releases over the course of 15 months for AT&T Wireless, generating \$190,000 in previously untapped professional service revenues
- Managed relationships and projects with customers and business partners including AT&T Wireless, Virgin Mobile, and FAST Search & Transfer
- Acquired, scoped, defined, produced, and communicated product requirements and user stories to drive agile software development in a SCRUM environment
- Initiated and championed implementation of company's first SCRUM management software, ScrumWorks, providing greater visibility into project status
- Acted as product team subject matter expert on search enabling technologies in support of sales initiatives

Program Manager

Dwango Wireless

2004 - 2006 (2 years)

- Managed text messaging initiatives, serving the role of both product and project manager
- Responsible for acquisition, management, and support of wireless devices, service, and specifications
- Built out formal games, ringtones and images publishing and distribution management program



Test Coordinator

AT&T

2003 - 2004 (1 year)

Promoted to manage on-site device testing program for AT&T Wireless

- Successfully supported the launch of wireless data services on over 25 new devices with as many as six in the development cycle at any given time
- Revised and developed new testing standards and documentation including requirements, test plans, and test cases
- Developed internal device tracking process that reduced human resource and device acquisition costs by over 30%, while increasing device availability
- Managed device and application defect tracking database, continually pushing defects to terminal states
- Initiated and managed outsourced testing processes with third-party vendors



Test Engineer

VeriTest

2003 - 2003 (less than a year)

Executed quality assurance testing on multiple projects including PC and wireless hardware, games, and localization

- Assisted test leads with training newly hired test engineers in Veritest testing processes and tools
- Implemented testing methodology to identify and document defects for easy communication with clients
- Participated in regularly scheduled "bug board" meetings to communicate and address issues with the team lead and fellow members

Education



B Lehigh University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Business Information Systems

Skills

Program Management • Mobile Applications • Cross-functional Team Leadership • Agile Methodologies • Testing • Mobile Devices • Scrum • Databases • Quality Assurance • Wireless